Nitu Kumari

Experience Summary

I have 4 Years 5 months of total and relevant experience in acting as **Business Analyst** as well as **Senior Business Development Executive** in IT Company, heading as a lead and managed the team effectively. As part of my assignments, I have been involved in gathering and documenting detailed requirements, preparing detailed proposals for clients, generating new business opportunities, interacting with technical lead, presenting detailed projects, etc. I have been a great part in developing business of the companies I worked with.

Education

Title of the Degree with Branch	College/University	Year of Passing
MBA in Information Technology	Lovely Professional University(Jalandhar, Punjab)	2012
Bachelors degree in Information Technology	Lovely Professional University(Jalandhar, Punjab)	2011
Class XII	Guru Gobind Singh Public School, CBSE (Bokaro Steel City, Jharkhand)	2007
Class X	Guru Gobind Singh Public School, CBSE (Bokaro Steel City, Jharkhand)	2005

Internship:

- 1) Research work at DESTIMONEY SECURITIES PVT LTD, AMRITSAR (duration: 6 weeks) as a part of MBA curriculum.
 - Studying the online trading software being used at Destimoney Securities Pvt Ltd.
 - Comparison with Power India Bulls online trading software.
- 2) Done practical training in IT Department of Bokaro Steel Plant/SAIL (duration: 4 weeks) as a part of BTECH curriculum.

Project Works:

- Website on Distributed Management System for Computer firm with HTML and ASP.net
- Payroll Management System with JAVA and MS Access

PAST EXPERIENCE

Organization: Sarna Technologies
Duration: September 2012 - July 2015

Role and Responsibilities

- Pre-sales analysis
- Requirement analysis and documentation.
- Creating sitemaps, flow diagram and wireframes as per the project requirement.
- Interaction with clients over Skype and query handling.
- Ample experience in online bidding and marketing, lead generation, conversion of leads into business and managing customers effectively.
- Managing and guiding the team and solving their issues.
- Interaction with technical lead and project creation.

Organization: CS Soft Solutions Pvt Ltd Duration: August 2015 - June 2016

Role and Responsibilities

- Online bidding on PHP based CMS and frameworks.
- Pre-sales analysis
- Lead generation, conversion of leads into business and managing customers effectively.
- Creating sitemaps, flow diagram and wireframes as per the project requirement.
- Client coordination and management.
- Interaction with technical lead.

Organization: Logic ERP Sales Pvt Ltd Duration: July 2016 - April 2017

Role and Responsibilities

- Pre-Sales Analysis.
- Lead generation, conversion of leads into business and managing customers effectively.
- Requirement analysis and documentation.
- Managing and guiding the team and solving their issues.
- Interaction with clients over Skype, Hangouts and query handling.
- Interaction with technical lead and project creation.

Competencies & Skills

- Excellent interpersonal skills with good verbal and written communication.
- Strong leadership qualities and problem solving skills.
- Ability to identify key or underlying issues in complex situations.
- Ability to lead and contribute within a team environment and strive to achieve team goals.
- Always strive to learn and practice new things.

Personal Details

Date Of Birth : 14th Jan, 1989 Father's Name : Mr. Vinay Bharti

Address : Jodhadih More Chas, Bokaro Steel City, Jharkhand. PIN: 827013

Language Proficiency: English, Hindi
E-mail ID : k.nitu03@gmail.com
Mobile No : +91-9501889263

Date: 2nd July 2018 Signature: Nitu Kumari